# **Nickolas Clymer**

Thornton, CO
nick\_clymer2018@yahoo.com
https://github.com/ncclymer
https://www.linkedin.com/in/nick-clymer-3148b4203
214-460-8219

I am a highly organized and motivated professional seeking a career in the computing industry. I am currently attending a web development bootcamp at the University of Denver. Areas of study include all front and backend aspects of web development. My previous work experience includes 11 years of customer service, B2B, and retail sales. I also have 11 years of warehousing and logistic experience. As a sales representative, I honed my interpersonal skills to facilitate sales and customer service goals. As a retail store manager, I developed staff members by using coaching and support dialog while filtering up and down communication when interacting with members of ownership. My primary goals have been providing a superior customer service experience, increasing total market share, cultural staff training, and timely order fulfillment.

# **Current Projects:**

https://ncclymer.github.io/06-Weather-dashboard/ HTML, CSS, Javascript https://ncclymer.github.io/05-Day-Planner-Project/ HTML, CSS, JavaScript https://domenicsw92.github.io/Have-You-Heard-Of/ HTML, CSS, Javascript

# **Work Experience:**

#### **Process assistant**

Amazon – Thornton, CO November 2019 to Present

AFE2 Process Assistant: partners with the senior leadership team in process design and implementation. Coordinates the skillsets of 80 to 120 associates into teams to achieve efficient customer order processing. Has oversight of associate job assignment to fulfill departmental needs while staying within labor budget constraints. Acts as an associate resource for: safety, HR, training, and process streamlining.

#### **Fulfillment Center Associate**

Problem Solve CPT Lead: monitors CPT's, product condition, collections, kick outs, force picks, pack from pops, and WIP chutes to ensure timely order processing, and execution of our customer promise. Also monitors product damage and inventory shortages.

AFE1 Sort Process Guide: monitors all aspects of the sort process which includes: conveyance tray count, MS totes, dwelling totes and trays, responds to sort AA andons, and clears tray sorter jams. Also actively communicates with PA and AM leadership teams to coordinate changes to pack wall counts. Actively communicates with jack pot and CE monitors to locate totes and products that are not physically present in AFE1 to reduce AA labor overhead and ensure timely processing of customer orders. Trained three other AA's to successfully fulfill the sort PG role. Lead AFE1 Waterspider: Trained and led the AFE1 waterspider team. Coached on safety and efficiency expectations. Coordinated wall assignments at start of shift. Conducted 5s projects to increase safety. AFE Packing and Sorting: works quickly to meet pack and sort rate expectations, and inspection of customer product for damage and overages. Resource to peers while working in process path.

## **Retail General Manager**

Appliance Factory & Mattress Kingdom – Longmont, CO April 2019 to November 2019

Engaged in creative process ideation to meet ownership requirements regarding labor cost and revenue through the following methods:

Best practice sales coaching resulted in an overall monthly store revenue increase of 18% and met ownership expectations of an increase in monthly mattress sales revenue of 6%.

Adaptive labor management through scheduling and employee incentives lowered hourly labor costs by 3% while still maintaining acceptable levels of staffing to meet customer needs.

Actively anticipated customer needs and concerns before they became an issue through effective process coaching and quality of work follow up regarding customer orders.

# **Retail General Manager**

TGS Management – Denver, CO March 2016 to January 2019

Provided sales and customer interaction training to new and established retail associates using known effective coaching techniques. Monthly store revenues increased by 25% from 750k to 1M gross product sales.

Retail sales associate KPI of per sale average increased from \$38 per transaction to \$49 per transaction. Higher sales averages of \$55-\$60 per transaction were achieved during peak seasonal events.

Proficient with Microsoft Office 365, using excel and SQL database imports to create a transaction heat map. Effective analytic use of the heat map tool lowered labor cost from 9% to 5%, and lowered customer wait times by 50% from 10 minutes to 5 by allocating employee labor to when it was needed most.

Familiar with retail logistics including regulated and unregulated product ordering, employee scheduling, facilities maintenance, daily cash handling, and conflict de-escalation.

# **Sales Representative**

Republic National Distributing Company - Grand Prairie, TX August 2007 to January 2015

Overall territory revenue increase of 45% from 1.4M to 1.9M annual gross sales and was achieved through the following methods:

Supported retailers with product flow management and retail floor customer assistance. This included shelf set recommendations to maximize profits on popular customer varietals. Average retail profit margins increased from 8% to 21%.

Developed excel spread sheet tools to track personal sales opportunities, deals in progress, and customer service objectives.

Increased territory productivity by organizing customer account routing geographically instead of preferentially. This increased the number of accounts on the route by 30% from 150 to 200 weekly stops and ensured regular customer visitation.

## **Warehouse Associate**

Kuehne & Nagel Logistics - Lewisville, TX May 1999 to August 2007

My duties at K&N included: Order selection, Product replenishment, Order accuracy verification, Powered equipment operation (electric and LP), General IT maintenance and repair, and order flow control management. At the end of my tenure with K&N I was the system super user and local support for the Database Administrator.

## Skills:

Front and back-end web application development including: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Node.js, Python, and SQL.

Other skills: time management, scheduling, employee skillset allocation, interviewing, fire and health code compliance, shelf set management, record keeping, invoicing, inventory control, Microsoft office suite, Tier 1 IT hardware issue resolution, employee coaching, and team motivation.

## **Education:**

University of Denver – Full stack web developer University of Denver - Denver, CO February 2021 to July 2021

University of North Texas - General Undergraduate

University of North Texas - Denton, TX September 1997 to January 1999

**High School**Macarthur High School - Irving, TX
August 1993 to May 1997

# **Professional references:**

Brendan Vickers – Amazon Area Manager bjvick@amazon.com

J.R. Starnes – Oracle Director of Risk Management Jstarnes3@yahoo.com